（小萌(こもえ)）
フフフン フフフン フフフ～ン♪
（青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）
ええい！　もう ちくしょう！
Man, screw this!
"What are the prerequisites for the ESP Card Experiment?"
（上条）
“ＥＳＰカード実験の必須条件”？
What makes you think a Level 0 like me would know that?
そんなこと レベル０の上条さんが
知ってると思うかよ？
Imagine Breaker...
（上条）
“幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)”
This mysterious power that resides in my right hand...
俺の右手に宿っている
摩訶不思議(まかふしぎ)な力
It can nullify any sort of supernatural power by mere touch.
それが異能の力であるならば―
触れただけで
打ち消すことができるらしい
だが こんなステキな力も―
However, this amazing power is useless when
it comes to completing my summer homework.
夏休みの宿題に対しては
何の効果もない
As if that weren't enough, Misaka Mikoto
forced me to go on a "date" with her,
しかも こんな日に限って―
御坂美琴(みさか みこと)に
恋人役の演技をしろと迫られるわ
アステカの魔術師に
追い回されるわと―
during which, an Aztec magician attacked us,
and it all went downhill from there.
さんざんな出来事が続き
そのため 実質的には…
Thanks to all of that...
I've barely done any of my homework.
宿題は ほとんど終わっていない
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
フフフン フフフン フフフ～ン♪
I see!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
なるほど
「超機動少女(マジカルパワード)カナミン」は
Magical Powered Kanami is using plastic to recreate
the Lotus Staff and the elemental parts of Ether!
エレメンタルにおける
パーツオブエーテル 蓮(はす)の杖を―
プラスチックで
再現しているということだね
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）すばらしきかな…
（上条）あの… インデックスさん
This Japanese style is just amazing!
Hello, Index-san?
別に“テレビ見るな”とか
言わないからさ
I'm okay with you watching TV, but
could you at least turn down the volume?
せめて ボリュームをだな…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻(とうま)は 全然 遊んでくれないし
Touma won't play with me at all!
Huh?
That's why I have to rely on the world of TV for entertainment!
だから 私はテレビの世界に
逃げ込んでいるというのに！
（上条）
ウワッ！
（当たる音）
（上条）あたっ…
ああ もう！　どうして お前は―
Damn it, why do you have to increase
my workload when I have no time?!
この時間がないときに
やることを増やすんですか？
あれ？　ちょっと… さっきの
やりかけのプリントは どこに？
Wait, what?
Where did that printout I was working on go?
What about my classical literature questions?
古文の問題集は？
数学の参考書は？　えっえっ…
And what about my math workbook?!
Oh, Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ 当麻！
（上条）オッ！　見つかったか？
Oh, did you find it?!
It's past three.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）もう３時過ぎなんだよ
（上条）えっ？
Huh?
I want a snack!
おやつ食べたいな
Such misfortune...
不幸だ…
（闇咲(やみさか)）
“Index-Librorum-Prohibitorum(インデックス・ライブロラム・プロヒビットラム)”
Index Librorum Prohibitorum.
The List of Prohibited Books...
“禁書目録”か
～♪
#01 The Last Day
August 31st
Boy, it sure was hard to find this printout in that pile of manga.
（インデックス）
いやぁ
大変だったんだよ
たくさんの漫画の
山の中から―
Hey, Touma, aren't I awesome?
プリントを捜し出すのは
Aren't I?
ねえ 当麻　私って偉い？　偉い？
何か言うことがあるんじゃないの？
ねえ ねえ
Don't you have something to say to me?
Well, don't you?
…で 結局 何が言いたいんだ？
So... what do you want?
I should be rewarded for all my hard work!
私は たくさん仕事をしたから
しかるべき報酬が欲しいんだよ
…ていうか 何か食べたい
Basically, I just wanna eat.
さっき
俺の分までプリン食っただろうが！
Didn't you just eat both our shares of pudding?!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ あれがいいかも
（上条）えっ？
That looks good!
Huh?
Hirayama Rami's
Five Hour Cooking
Soybean Richness
How to Make a Tofu Salisbury Steak
Today, we'll be making a Tofu Salisbury Steak in under five hours!
（平山）
今日は５時間かけて
作る豆腐ハンバーグです
Didn't I already tell you that I don't have that kind of time?!
だから そんな物作ってる時間は
ないんだって！
It's already past five... meaning there are
only seven more hours left in the day...
現在 午後５時過ぎ
日付変更まで 約７時間
Even if I pull an all nighter, there'll be less than
fifteen hours before I have to go to school!
完全徹夜を覚悟したところで
学校へ行くまで あと15時間もない
During which, I nee—
Touma.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻
（上条）えっ？
It's not good to force yourself into a corner.
あんまり根詰めるのは
よくないんだよ
The more irritated you become, the less you'll be able to focus.
カリカリすると
余計に頭回らなくなっちゃうかも
ムリしないで
Don't push yourself too hard.
お前にだけは言われたくない
I don't want to hear that from you!
So it's here...
ここか
String of the Wind Demon!
風魔の弦
String of Destruction!
衝打の弦
フゥ…
いない？
It's not here...
何かイヤな予感がする
I have a bad feeling about something...
Hey, Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻 当麻！　これ
何でも頼んじゃっていいのかな？
Can I order anything I want?
何だよ？　何がいいんだよ？
Well, what do you want?
それじゃ いちばん高いの！
（猫の鳴き声）
I want... the most expensive dish on the menu!
Alright, then. 2,000 yen worth of raw eggs.
じゃ 生卵を2,000円分っと…
当麻！
Touma!
（上条）
わたくし 上条当麻と
インデックスの２人は―
Index and I, Kamijou Touma, went to a
family restaurant for a change of scenery.
気分転換も兼ねてファミレスへ
I decided to tackle the rest of my summer homework, but...
俺は 夏休みの宿題の
残党狩りに取りかかったのだったが
Sorry for the wa—
（ｳｴｰﾄﾚｽ）
お待たせいたしまし…
（闇咲）
そこか
So it's there...
Off to the battlefield.
いざ 戦場(いくさば)へ
（上条）
俺の…
俺の能力開発概論のレポートが…
My report on the theory of ability development...
Um... I'll bring something to clean it up right away!
（ｳｴｰﾄﾚｽ）
あの… ただいま
拭く物を持ってまいりますので
で… でも 当麻
まだ文字は読めるんだし
B-But Touma, you can still read the characters,
so you can still use it to copy your work onto another page!
新しい原稿用紙に丸写しすれば
使い物になるんだよ
I wrote three pages worth, too...
イチから内容を考え直す手間が
省けたと思えば
Isn't it a good thing that you can go
over the whole thing while you're at it?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）なんとも お得だね
（上条）うん？
（上条）ハッ…
（闇咲）開戦の のろしを上げん
I declare the Curse of Battle Initiation.
String of Demon Termination!
断魔の弦！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）アッ！
（ｳｴｰﾄﾚｽ）ヒイッ！
（闇咲）うん？
（上条）ハァハァ… てめえ…
You bastard...
何しやが… あっ…
What the hell do you—
（闇咲）こちらだ
（上条）あっあっ…
I'm over here.
この結果は予想外だが
無益な殺生が減るなら喜ぼう
This result was certainly unexpected.
However, the fewer deaths, the better.
If you surrender right now, I will not hurt you.
このまま投降すれば
（闇咲）君には手を出さない
（上条）うん？
All I need is—
目的の物さえ手に入れ…
M-My homework...
お… 俺の… 俺の宿題が紙吹雪に…
became... confetti...
おい！　そこのお前！
Hey, you! This is your fault, so you fix it!
お前がやったんだから
お前が責任取れ
俺の宿題 お前がやれよ！
You're doing my homework for me!
Like hell I am.
（闇咲）知ったことか
（上条）ハッ…
ＯＫ　今日の上条さんは
ちょっとばかしバイオレンスですよ
Okay, then.
Kamijou-san will just have to use a bit more violence today...
（上条）…て あれ？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）アッ！
Wait, what?
Let me cut to the chase.
（闇咲）
手短に済ます
子供の遊びにつきあう気はない
I do not wish to engage in child's play.
なに考えてんだ てめえ
インデックスをどうするつもりだ？
What do you want?
What are you going to do to Index?!
分かるだろう？　これが
10万3,000冊を記憶している―
You should already know.
That is, if you do know that herein lies
the list of 103,000 prohibited books.
禁書目録だと知りうるならば
Are you a magician?
お前 魔術師か
Yes, I am.
（闇咲）いかにも
（上条）ハッ…
String of the Ghost Horse!
透魔の弦
なっ… 待て この野郎！　ンッ！
Goddamn it, wait!
（触れる音）
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）イヤ！
（上条）
ハッ…
何か小さくて柔らかい物が
There's something small and soft!
…て そこにいるのか？
インデックス
Is that you, Index?
（姫神(ひめがみ)）
な… なに？
W-What was that?
Damn, he got me.
くそ　やられた
（ｳｴｰﾄﾚｽ）あの… お客さま
（上条）うん？
Excuse me, sir?
（上条）
ヒイッ！
I didn't give her a cell phone for something like this, but...
こんなときのために 携帯
持たせたわけじゃなかったんだけど
つながるはずねえか　くそ！
She probably can't answer...
Damn!
一体 どこを捜せば…
（猫の鳴き声）
Where do I even begin looking?
えっ？　おい！
H-Hey!
Hey, where are you going, Sphinx?!
（上条）
おい！
どこに行くんだ スフィンクス！
Wait up!
待てよ！
（上条）
ホテル？
A hotel?
Is Index there?
まさか ここにインデックスが…
She's over there, Sphinx?!
そっちなのか？　スフィンクス
（上条）
そこか！　インデックス！
There?!
Index!
You bastard!
ぼらぁ！　貴様は
飼い主に対する恩義とかねえのか！
Do you not feel any gratitude at all towards your owner?!
仮にも てめえを拾ったのは
インデックスだろうが！
Wasn't it Index who picked you from the streets?!
ほら さっさと捜しに行くぞ
Come on, we're going to go look for her.
（闇咲）
驚いたな　この短時間で
結び目を２つも解いたのか
Impressive.
You were able to undo two knots in such a short amount of time.
Ropes are but a mere form of torture unique to Japan.
縄は日本が生んだ独自の
拷問文化だけど
It will take more than this to make me speak!
こんな雑な方法じゃ
私は しゃべらないんだよ
（闇咲）
言ったはずだ
君を拷問することが目的ではない
I think I already said my aim wasn't to torture you.
All I want is to obtain one of the many grimoires inside of you.
君の中にある魔道書
その１冊を手に入れたいのだ
さて…
Now...
I'll need to cast an amplification field.
（闇咲）
まずは
増幅のための結界を―
張らねばならない
あの魔術師 インデックスを
どうするつもりなんだ？
That damned magician...
What's he going to do to Index?
くそ！　どこを捜せばいいんだよ！
Damn it! Where should I look?!
（上条）ウワッ！
（美琴）アッ！
S-Sorry about that!
わ… 悪い　あっ…
…て あんた
こんな所で何やってんのよ？
Hey! What are you doing here?!
Good grief.
…たく　なんか いっつも
どっか走り回ってるみたいだけど
You always seem to be running off somewhere.
You should at least let me know if you're okay.
無事なら無事って
連絡入れなさいよね
Oh, that's right. I never gave you my cell phone number, did I?
そういえば あんた
私の携帯番号 知らなかったっけ？
H-Huh?!
…て えっ あれ？
（爆発音）
（上条）ウワッ！
まったく
いつも いつも あんたは…
Sheesh. It's always the same with you.
ふざけてんじゃないわよ
Stop messing around!
…て あれ？　あんた なに本気で
泣きそうになってんのよ？
Wait, what?
Why do you look like you're about to cry?
急いでんだよ 思いっきり！
I'm seriously in a hurry!
With homework and kidnappings and family restaurant mayhem!
宿題とか 人さらいとか
ファミレスの騒ぎとか！
So, what the hell do you want?
（上条）それで 何の用なんだ？
（美琴）えっ？　あっ なに？
Oh, well, uh...
It's... just...
いや その…
I got upset because you weren't talking to me...
単に 相手にされなかったのが
ムカついただけで
特に これといって
用事があるわけじゃないんだけど
It's not like I wanted to talk to you or anything, but...
Not like... I wanted to talk to you, but...
あるわけじゃないんだけど …さ
Sorry!
（上条）ごめん！
（美琴）えっ？
ねえ ちょっと！
あんた 本気で行っちゃうわけ？
Hey! Are you seriously going to just take off?!
ねえってば！
I'm talking to you!
Is this a Kagura dance stage?
（インデックス）
これは神楽舞台？
（闇咲）
そんな
大それた代物ではない
It's not as big as that.
さしずめ 盆踊りの
会場といったところだな
It's closer to the size of a Bon Odori stage.
そんなものを用意して
私に何かを憑(つ)かせる気？
So you're going to use this to possess me or something?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ…
（闇咲）なぁに
Not at all.
I cast this field to slightly amplify the power of this.
結界を張ったのは
こいつの威力を―
少々 増強しようという魂胆だ
（プッシュ音）
The Azusa Bow?
梓弓(あずさゆみ)？　日本神道で使う礼装だね
It's used in Japanese Shinto ceremonies.
うん？　すばらしい
Amazing... your knowledge even covers our culture.
こちらの文化圏も
カバーしているのか
（闇咲）
その魔道書図書館は…
This used to have just enough power to
shock one's soul, thus rectifying warping.
Index? Hey, Index. Can you hear me? Where are you?!
インデックス？　インデックス？
（上条）
おい 聞こえないのか？
今どこにいるんだ？
（闇咲）
ゆがみを正す程度の力しかない
However, if certain conditions are met...
（闇咲）
しかし 条件さえそろえば
相手の心を詳細に読むことができる
I can use this to elaborately read one's soul.
That's right.
そう
胸の内に 必死に隠している―
I can even force myself to the 103,000
grimoires that hide deep within your heart.
10万3,000冊を暴くことなどもな
ダ… ダメ！
Y-You can't!
私以外の人間が魔道書に触れれば
どうなるか―
Don't you know what would happen if someone
else were to touch one of the grimoires?
あなただって分かってるでしょう？
無論 百も承知
Of course I do.
I know very well what will happen.
（ノイズ）
ウワッ！
What was that?
何だ？
さっきのホテルじゃねえか
Isn't that the hotel I went to earlier?!
くそ！
Shit!
それは「抱朴子(ほうぼくし)」
中国文化における不老不死―
That's Houbokushi.
A grimoire used in Chinese culture that allows
one to become an enlightened immortal.
仙人になるための魔道書
The Chinese alchemy in it allows one to create
a potion capable of curing any disease.
あらゆる病や呪いを解く薬を作る
錬丹術が載っている
（闇咲）ゴホッ…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ハッ…
I thought I could do anything if I became a magician...
魔術師になれば
何でもできると思っていた
I refused to give up because of a curse,
thus I swore to become a magician.
もう二度と
挫折したくないと思ったから
魔術師になることを誓った
At the very least... not for this...!
少なくとも
こんなことのためではない
A woman was dying due to some unknown curse.
何かの呪いによって
死にかけている女がいた
She was a helpless and worthless person who
could only smile in the face of imminent death.
目前に迫る死に対して
ほほえむことしかできない―
無力な つまらない人間だ
こんな つまらない人間も
助けれないで―
Being unable to save such a worthless person isn't
about what I can do or whether I'm giving up!
“何でもできる”も
“挫折したくない”もない
I can't give up the dream I've been chasing
after for such a worthless woman!
こんな つまらない女のために―
自分が今まで大事に育ててきた夢に
キズをつけるなんて
It's definitely not for that worthless woman.
決して
あんなつまらない女のためではない
It's definitely not because of that worthless woman!
絶対に
あんなつまらない女のせいではない
You're wrong!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）違うよ
（闇咲）ハッ…
I know.
私は分かる
その梓弓 威力が増幅されすぎて
あなたの心が私の中に逆流している
Your Azusa Bow's strength has become so
amplified that I can see what's in your heart.
That's why I know... that you loved her.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
だから 分かるもの
あなたは
ただ その女の人が好きだった
That's why you wanted to save her, even if it'd cost you your life.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
だからこそ
命を懸けても助けたかった
You had to hurt others and commit sins in order to save her.
助けるためには 他人を傷つけて
罪を犯さなければならなかった
But you didn't want to place the blame on her.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
だから その責任を―
その女の人に押しつけたくなかった
That's why you can't die here!
だったら
あなたは破滅しちゃいけないんだよ
こんな薄汚れた魔道書に
頼るなんて方法じゃダメ！
Don't rely on this unclean grimoire!
Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻！
（上条）ンンッ！
Touma! Touma!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻！　当麻！
（上条）…たく 心配させやがって
Sheesh. You really made me worry.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻 おなか減った
Touma, I'm hungry!
（上条）
あとで腹いっぱい水飲ませてやる
I'll let you drink all the water you can handle later.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻！
Touma!
（闇咲）悪いのか？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ･上条）うん？
Was I wrong?
The thought of protecting someone
even if it meant risking my life...
たとえ
この命と引き換えにしてでも―
誰かを守りたいと思うのは
悪いことなのか？
Is that really wrong?!
Of course it is!
悪いに決まってる
You already know the pain of losing someone dear.
（上条）
あんた 知ってんだろう？
大切な誰かに死なれることの痛みが
The pain of seeing someone suffer, getting hurt...
（上条）
目の前で誰かが苦しんで 傷ついて
But being unable to do anything...
でも 自分には何もできなくて
You know the pain of being powerless, don't you?
どうしようもないっていう苦しみを
知ってんだろう？
You probably panicked...
（上条）
焦ったはずだ　つらかったはずだ
You probably couldn't take it...
You probably suffered...
苦しかったはずだ　痛かったはずだ
You probably felt pain...
怖かったはずだ　震えたはずだ
叫んだはずだ　涙が出たはずだ
You were probably scared...
You probably started shaking...
You probably screamed...
And you probably cried...
But that's wrong!
だったら それはダメだ
そんなに重たい衝撃は―
You can't place such a heavy shock on someone else!
誰かに
押しつけちゃいけないものなんだ！
（闇咲）
まったく…
Goddamn it...
Just by reading one book...
（闇咲）
たった１冊 読み取った程度で…
I suppose it's impossible for someone as insignificant
as me to obtain even one prohibited book.
土台 私ごときの小さな器では―
原典１冊すら入手することは
不可能だったわけだ
フフフッ…
私の人生は挫折ばかりだ
My life is filled with failure...
人生で もう３度も諦めてしまった
I've already given up three times...
フッ… それでも
諦められないものがあったのだ
But even so... there was but one thing that I couldn't give up on.
ただひとつ
それだけのことだったのだが
Just one, but...
アア… あいた あいた…
（上条）
なに １人で きれいに
話 終わらせようとしてんだ
Why are you wrapping up the story all by yourself?
（闇咲）いたっ！
（上条）今のは夏休みの宿題の分
That was for my summer homework.
Seriously.
…たく
お前のせいで 宿題は もう絶望的だ
Because of you, there's no way I can finish my homework now.
（上条）
それで お前の大切な人ってのは
どこにいるんだよ？
So, where's that "important person" of yours?
What?
なに？
だから
禁書目録なんて使わなくても―
I'm saying we can still do something...
even without the use of prohibited books.
なんとかなるんだっつうの
Didn't you see what my right hand can do?
あんたも見たろう この右手
I'm no magician, so I don't know what curses are exactly.
俺は魔術師じゃねえから―
呪いってのが
どんなもんかは知らねえけど
こいつを使えば 呪いなんざ
一発で消えちまうんじゃねえか？
But I'm sure my right hand will instantly dispel any curse.
T-Th-That's ridiculous!
（闇咲）
なっ… アア… バカな
I don't really understand it either.
（上条）
俺だって よく分かんねえけど
この右手は そういうものなんだ
But that's what my right hand does.
So...
（上条）
さてと…
そんじゃ 案内してもらうぜ
Take us to where she is.
We'll save that important person of yours.
あんたの大切な人は 必ず助け出す
そのためには
あんたの協力が必要なんだ
And for that, we'll need your help.
That's why you'll have to lend us a hand.
（上条）
だから
意地でも手を貸してもらうぜ
Don't you want to save her with your own hands?
あんただって 助けたいんだろう？
自分自身の手で
Good grief...
まったく… 魔術だの 呪いだの
Being pulled around by magic, curses, and
all these other random occurrences.
ワケの分からないもんに
振り回されやがって
そんな くらだねえ幻想を―
So let's go destroy all of those pathetic illusions!
みんな まとめて
ぶち殺しに行こうぜ
Have you... no idea...
～♪
who... you just... attacked?!
（騎士Ａ）
分かって …いるのか？
貴様が今 攻撃したのは
一体 誰なのかを
I can't believe the Knights of England are already down.
（土御門(つちみかど)）
まったく… 英国ご自慢の騎士が
このありさまだとはな
Have you come to stop me?
（神裂(かんざき)）
私を止めに来ましたか？
No one told me to stop you.
（土御門）
俺は ねーちん個人を
止めるようには言われてないし
I also have my own work to do.
こっちは
こっちの仕事があるんだぜ
Is that an order from the Church of England or Academy City?
（神裂）
それは イギリス清教と学園都市
どちらの命令ですか？
（土御門）
さてね
Who knows?
Well, if you were to think about it, I think you'd figure it out.
まあ 常識で考えれば
すぐ分かると思うぜ
Rather, you'd know immediately if
you think about who I'm a spy for.
つうか 俺が どっちの
スパイなのかを考えりゃ―
すぐに分かるわな
I'm leaving.
（神裂）
私は もう行きます
上へ報告したければ ご自由に
I won't stop you if you wish to inform the higher-ups.
Is that so?
（土御門）
そうかい…
ああ 連中は回収しとくぜい
Then I'll clean up these folks.
Thank you.
（神裂）
恩に着ます
…でさ 結局 ねーちんは―
So, why did you come all the way here from England?
イギリスから 遠路はるばる
何しに来たんだにゃ？
Who knows?
（神裂）
さあ？
Next Episode
Index has suddenly been kidnapped,
（上条）
突如 連れ去られるインデックス
学園都市の外で進む巨大な謀略
and something big is happening just outside of Academy City.
What are the true intentions of the group after Orsola Aquinas?
オルソラ＝アクィナスを狙う組織の
真の目的とは？
Next time: "The Book of the Law."
次回 「法の書」
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる